Noel Baron

Senior Architect, Full Stack Developer Remote Telecommute, DeLand Florida www.noelbaron.com - noel@goodfellaz.com - 908.377.5046

Summary:

I am a senior architect & team leader with emphasis on Javascript and PHP stacks. I have personally built many large-scale applications and am a veteran of B2B and B2C software development lifecycles with 15 years of hands-on experience.

Education:

Rutgers University – Information Systems, Computer Science

Full Stack Technologies

- Node JS, NPM
- Socket.io
- Express, Apache 2, NGINX
- MySQL, NoSQL, MSSQL
- Redis, Memcached
- IONIC Mobile, Appcelerator Mobile
- Service Oriented Architecture
- JQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, AJAX
- PHP, LAMP, Ruby on Rails
- CSS2, CSS3, HTML5
- Capistrano, Chef, SpiderCD
- Linux, Mac, Mobile, Tablet
- D3 Charts & Visualizations
- Flash Actionscript

- Mocha, Request, xUnit
- Object Oriented Programming
- Restful API Design
- Advanced Client-Side Javascript
- Service Oriented Architecture
- Continuous Integration
- Continuous Deployment
- Various Full Stack Frameworks
- Test-Driven Development
- Behavioral-Driven Development
- Third Party API Abstraction
- Github Integration, etc.
- Resposive Design

Systems Administration

- Cloud Infrastructure
- Amazon Web Services
- EC2 (Classic and VPC)
- SES Email Service
- Route 52 DNS Management
- PRIV/DMZ Setup & Maintenance
- MySQL Master/Slave, Amazon RDS
- Elasticache (Redis, Memcached)
- SOLR
- Yum Repository Management
- Node Package Manager
- Github Webhooks & Services

Process, Preferences, and Management

- Agile Methodologies
- Kanban Work In Progress
- Scrum Team SDLC
- XP, Peer Programming
- Waterfall
- Continuous Deployment

- Automated Testing
- MVC Frameworks
- Rapid Development
- · Cloud Infrastructure
- Remote Teams
- No Gantt Charts, Ever!

Experience on page 2.

Experience

Full Stack Consultant, Big Data, Senior Architect

Consultant (2014 – 2015)

Executed SDLC for a variety of clients in Manhattan, Los Angeles, and San Francisco. Responsible for end-to-end design, service oriented architecture, automated testing/deployment, database design/refactor, product/project management responsibilities, peer review, and other leadership roles typically attributed to in-house Tech Directors and CTOs.

Extensive focus on full-tilt Javascript (Node, Socket.io, Jquery, Angular, D3, Mocha, etc). Extensive focus on API-powered applications.

Extensive focus on cloud infrastructure (AWS – All services).

Moderate focus on D3 visualizations, Big Data Business Intelligence

Achieve 3000 – Differentiated Online Learning

Sr Full Stack Architect (2013 – 2014)

Designed an intricate collection of backend services to provide their flagship 5-step browser-based literacy program to students via a native iPad app. Created a restful API to act as the interface for receiving online *and* stored offline iPad data. The API also managed conflicts between old vs. current data. The January 2014 launch was successful and was met with much fanfare, and the API outperformed Achieve's existing systems 10-to-1. The service is currently being extended to power other projects at Achieve.

Goodfellaz Internet Services – Technology & Process Consulting

Managing Director (1996 - 2002) Managing Director (2007 – 2013)

Acted as managing director, leading process consultant, and full stack developer. Conceived & managed over 100 early stage product life-cycles for new & existing startups. Often stepped in as temporary CTO & process consultant for new companies while they established in-house teams. Oversaw countless deployments of web, API, and mobile code using custom AWS solutions and standard deployment & code management techniques. Clients include Sprint, Mitel, AOL, and a large collection of small startups.

Clique Communications, LLC

Research & Development Engineer (2004 - 2005) Lead Web Engineer (2005-2006) Solutions Group Manager (2006-2007) Product Owner, Process Strategist (2007-2008)

Engineered a number of prototype multimedia applications based on COM/ActiveX h264 video processing components. Applications were built to run in a web browser, utilizing JavaScript, DHTML, PHP, SQL, and server-side Java. Prototyped applications include personal video broadcasting, streaming television, video greeting cards, multipoint video conferencing, video blogging, and video discussion forums.